Hoo-ya!
呼呀！
Oh!
噢！
Munched!
带劲！
Give it up for the baddest beast machines on the planet!
为这星球上最庞大的机器巨兽欢呼吧！
Would you mind lowering the volume?
行行好把音量调低点行吗？
Hey, Ratch,
嘿 救护车
check out the monster truck rally Miko took me to last week.
来看看上个星期神子带我去看的怪兽卡车拉力赛
I compiled some highlights with my cell phone.
我在手机上存了些精彩片段
Innocent vehicles battling for the pleasure of human spectators?
无辜的车辆为了取悦人类观众而互相厮杀？
Blood sport!
太暴力了！
- Yea!
- 没错！
You could be helping Optimus in the field right now.
你应该去野外给擎天柱搭把手
Ah, he doesn't need my help to search for some ancient educational¡­
啊 他用不着我去找什么古代教育的…
¡­ thingamabob.
…鬼东西
The "thingamabob" to which you refer happens to be a Cybertronian data cylinder.
你嘴里的这个“鬼东西”正是塞博特恩的数据经筒
Hey!
嘿！
And there is no telling what vast intelligence it may hold.
这其中浩瀚的智慧根本无法言喻
During the Golden Age,
在黄金时代
dozens of these cylinders were created,
许多这样的经筒被制造出来
each containing the sum total of Cybertronian knowledge on any given subject:
每一个都储藏着塞博特恩的所有知识 涵盖一切科目
stellar cartography, medicine, ancient mythology.
恒星成像学 医学 古神话…
When the war broke out,
后来战争爆发
the cylinders were hidden throughout the galaxies,
这些经筒被隐匿到各个星系
to keep them as far as possible from Decepticon reach.
以防被霸天虎染指
Detecting one signal here,
能在这里探测到一个经筒
on Earth, is the opportunity of a...
在地球上 就有可能…
Eh... T.M.I., dude.
呃… 你话太多了 哥们
Switch it back, I want to see the hoedown showdown.
把频道调回去 我想看完这整场节目
Ratchet, Decepticon ambush!
救护车 有霸天虎的埋伏！
The cylinder is at risk!
经筒有危险
We require backup!
我们需要支援
Backup is what I'm built for.
我天生就是提供支援的
Go bend some fenders, Bulk.
砸了他们的挡泥板 小隔
I have an important mission for you, too. Miko.
我也有个重要的任务要交给你 神子
Really?
真的？
Agh...
啊…
Autobots, stand your ground.
汽车人 坚守阵地
the artifact must not fall into enemy hands!
这件文物绝对不能落入敌手！
Come to papa.
到爸爸这来
Run to mommy!
回你妈那去
Say uncle. Say it!
叫叔叔 快叫！
Ratchet, come in!
救护车 回话！
Miko? This is an emergency channel.
神子？这可是紧急频道
We need to keep it open for the Auto... Wait...
我们得保持它畅通 以防… 等等…
Where are you?
你在哪里？
D'oy! I'm with the thingamabob!
我就在那鬼东西旁边
Thingama... the data cylinder!
鬼东…数据经筒！
Yes, can you bridge it out of here?
没错 你能把这东西从这带走吗？
I'll reactivate arrival coordinates.
我会重新启动你那里的坐标
Dude, can you open it any closer?
老兄 你能把它开得再近一点吗？
Supply coordinates.
给我提供坐标
Ugh... Fifty yards?
呃… 五十码？
Precise coordinates!
精确的坐标！
One, two, Hahhhhh...
一 二 哈啊啊啊…
Whoa...
哇噢…
Miko?
神子？
No!
不！
Bulk!
小隔！
You really took one for the team, Bulkhead,
你真是员得力干将 隔板
my team.
不过是我们这边的
Bulkhead, are you¡­
隔板 你没事吧？
Fine. I didn't even smart.
没事 像挠了一下痒痒
I helped loose that thing.
我帮了倒忙把那东西弄丢了
I want to help find it.
我想帮忙去找
I need to get back in the field with Optimus.
我要去现场协助擎天柱
You are under my watch now -- Optimus' orders.
你现在要接受我的监护 这是擎天柱的命令
And running a full scan of your neural network would be a wiser use of your time.
花点时间给你做个神经网络大检查才是明智之举
Come on, doc.
拜托 医生
There's nothing up there to scan.
没什么好检查的
He seems fine to me.
我感觉他挺好
Well, if you insist on making yourself useful.
好吧 如果你一定要干点什么
You can help Miko tidy up.
你可以帮神子一起打扫
Ughhh!
呃！
He's mad with power!
简直是鸡毛当令箭！
Hehehe, that's Ratchet.
呵呵呵 救护车就是那样的
Null vector squared, alright?
零向量平方 是吧？
What?
什么？
Hey, we got any paint around here?
嘿 我们有油漆吗？
Art project? Cool!
你要搞艺术？酷！
What do you mean "it's empty"?
你说“它是空的”是什么意思？
Lord Megatron,
威震天陛下
these cylinders are not unlike batteries.
这些经筒就像电池一样
The data is stored within them as a form of energy.
数据以某种能量形式存储在里面
It's scanned fully charged.
刚扫描到的时候它还是满的
That's how we located it to begin with.
所以我们才能对它定位
But now...
但是现在…
Dead battery.
废电池一只
Did you drop it, you one-eye oaf?
是你摔的吗 独眼白痴？
No, master.
不是的 主人
I wasn't gonna touch the thing after it put a zap on Bulkhead.
我还没来得及碰 它就给隔板来了一下子
Hey, you think...
嘿 你想会不会…
I know.
我懂了
And I must find out what that vessel contained.
我必须弄清楚这个罐子到底装过什么东西
When it comes to the secrets of the ancients,
在那些古人的秘密中
knowledge can be power.
知识也是力量
Seriously, Ratch,
我是认真的 救护车
you need to see what Bulk's painting in here.
你得来看看隔板画的东西
Yes, I'm sure "one hasn't truly lived until one¡®s beheld
好吧 要是不见识一下隔板的钢铁人生
Bulkhead's take on steel life with lugnuts".
就算是白活了
See, did I tell you or what?
看 我跟你说什么来着？
The differential of one third r cubed is r-dr-r
三分之一的r立方求导得到r dr r
That is not art.
那不是艺术
It's science.
是科学
This hot spot you see here.
你看到的这个红点
It's information, data, living energy.
这是信息 数据 活生生的能量
Hold on. It's alive, it's on fire,
等一下 你说这是活的 还很旺盛
and it's in Bulkhead's brain?
而且还在隔板脑子里？
Chill, Miko.
冷静点 神子
The data is only inhabiting a fraction of my brain.
数据仅仅是寄宿在我大脑的一部分空间内
Infinitesimal by standard neural net densities.
相比神经网络的密度规模就是无穷小
Wait... how do I know all that?
等等… 我怎么懂这些东西？
Based on what we witness during our skirmish,
从战斗时发生的事看来
the living data must have been programmed to eject
这种活生生的数据肯定设定了程序
when it sensed unauthorized access.
当感知到异常接触的时候就发射出去
A security measure.
安全措施
It would have jettisoned heavenward.
它本来要向空中发射
Lost to the stars.
消失在星际之间
Except my fat engine block got in the way.
没想到我的胖引擎挡住了路
Every Con there made a grab for it.
每个在场的虎子都拿过它
But the cylinder doesn't go off until Miko touches it?
但经筒只在神子碰了之后才启动的？
The cylinders originated from Cybertron's Golden Age,
经筒起源于塞博特恩的黄金时代
pre-dating the Autobot-Decepticon division.
那时还没有汽车人和霸天虎之分
So it wouldn't consider any native of Cybertron to be a threat.
所以它不会把任何塞博特恩人当成威胁
Only alien life forms, such as humans.
只有外星生命体 比如人类
Are we staring at genius, or gibberish?
那这些是高深理论 还是胡话？
I do not wish to falsely rally anyone's hopes,
尽管可能是空欢喜一场
but these equations appear to be the formula for a synthetic Energon.
但这些工式似乎是人造能量的方程式
We hit the mother lode?
我们挖到宝了？
Miko, do you understand what this means?
神子 你明白这意味着什么吗？
Um...
呃…
Energon provides our fuel,
能量给我们提供燃料
our ammo, our life force.
弹药 还有我们的生命力量
With the natural stuff in such short supply here on Earth,
地球上天然的能量如此稀缺
this could solve a whole lot of problems.
这可以解决许许多多的问题
Such as, providing us with the edge we need to turn the tide of this war.
比如 提供为我们逆转战争形势的优势
Or, handing us the key to revitalizing Cybertron.
或者 获得复兴塞博特恩的关键技术
We got the goods,
我们拿到了实物
and all Megatron got was an empty bucket.
而威震天所拿到的只有一个空罐子
How often do I get to use my knocking to save the day?
我何曾有过用脑子还能大显身手的时候？
Intersection of atomic coordinates indicate convergent tertiary structures.
原子坐标的交点显示出收敛的三级结构
- Are you done yet? - Simply converting data is irreversible,
- 你还没写完吗？ - 简单转化数据是不可逆的
resulting in asymmetric...
最终产生不对称…
Got to admit,
不得不说
it's weird seeing Bulk in brainiac mode.
聪明模式的隔板感觉有点奇怪
Vector L norm squared.
向量L模值的平方
Break time!
休息时间！
How about a lightening round of T.M.T. street racer 7?
来场风驰电掣的街头赛车7如何？
Energon temperatures in volume proportional... angle trisector construction.
能量温度与体积比例… 三分角技巧
Got another round for you to log, Ratchet.
又该你记录了 救护车
This is Bulkhead's neural net as you saw it earlier.
上一次我们看到隔板的神经网络是这样的
This scan was recorded just minutes ago.
这是几分钟前新的扫描记录
It is as I feared --
我担心的就是这个――
-- the data seems to be actively and aggressively
这些数据正在积极地 侵蚀性地
re-writing Bulkhead's neural net.
重写隔板的神经网络
I had hoped he was purging the data,
我曾指望他能清除数据
but he seems to be merely transcribing it, as it...
但他似乎只顾着照抄这些数据 而这些数据
Consumes his mind.
正在占据他的思维
From all indications,
所有迹象表明
by the time Bulkhead completes the formula,
当隔板完成方程式时
his own thought, his memories,
他自己的思想 他的记忆
could be wiped clean.
都会被抹掉
But if we stop him,
但是如果我们阻止了他
good-bye synthetic Energon.
那就等于挥别了人造能量
You assume we possess a means of stopping him.
前提是我们能找到阻止他的方法
I don't exactly have instant access to the wisdom of the ancients.
我还不能立即理解古人的智慧
I will not allow another one of our own to be sacrificed.
我不能容忍又一个战友牺牲
No matter the cost.
不惜一切代价
If the living data transmitted itself from the cylinder,
如果这些有生命的数据把自己从经筒里传输出来
perhaps we could somehow coaks it back inside.
也许我们能 用些什么办法把它再塞回去
How are we supposed to get it back from the Decepticons?
我们又怎么从霸天虎手中夺回经筒？
Megatron will bring it to us.
威震天会主动送过来的
Friction coefficient quotient of the subset amplified...
子集放大后的摩擦系数值…
You want amplified?
想要放大音量吗？
Proving perceptor's paradox is nothing of a kind.
证明观测者悖论在此处不适用…
Nah! What is that?
啊！怎么回事？
Metal. You loved this song.
金属 你喜欢这首歌
I'm trying to concentrate.
我需要集中精力
Ughh... You are starting to sound just like Ratchet!
呃… 你的口气越来越像救护车了！
Who?
谁？
Ratch, I think Bulk's losing his mind.
救护车 我觉得隔板有些失去理智了
You... already know...
你… 已经知道了…
Miko, we didn't want to frighten you,
神子 我们不想吓到你
but rest assured,
不过你放心
Optimus has a plan.
擎天柱已经有计划了
Optimus isn't Bulkhead's doctor.
擎天柱不是隔板的医生
I just need to know,
我只想知道
when Bulk's done spitting out that formula,
等隔板念完那些方程式
he'll go back to being regular old Bulkhead, right?
他会重新变回原来那个隔板 对吗？
Lord Megatron, we've detected a familiar energy profile.
威震天陛下 我们探测到了一个熟悉的能量信号
The data?
数据的？
Bulkhead must have left the shielded radius of their base.
隔板离开了他们基地的保护屏障
Breakdown and I will...
打击和我要去…
Fail me again?
再搞砸一次？
Optimus.
擎天柱
You're certainly not the Autobot I expected to find here.
显然你不是我想见到的汽车人
But let me guess --
不过 让我猜猜――
you rigged the transponder to mimic the frequency of the data I seek.
你装备了发射器 伪造了我想找的数据信号
Megatron, I have a proposal.
威震天 我有个提议
I'm¡­ listening.
但说无妨
Surrender the cylinder,
交出经筒
and I will return it to you fully restored.
我会把它重新充满 并还给你
This trinket right here?
这个小玩意儿？
And pray tell,
请你告诉我
what trifles did it hold that you are so anxious to give away?
它到底装了什么不祥之物 你如此急于脱手？
Accept my terms, and you will find out.
接受我的提议 你自然就知道了
Do you remember the time you watched Wheeljack lobbed his only grenade into Decepticon heat-exchanger?
你还记得千斤顶将他唯一的手雷 扔进霸天虎热交换机的场景吗？
Who?
谁？
Wheeljack! Your best bud--
千斤顶！你最好的伙伴…
beside me, of course.
当然 除了我以外的
Do you even know who I am?
你还知道我是谁吗？
Of course, you're...
当然 你是…
Equivalent to the Fr¨¦chet mean of the oblate spheroid to the N power.
等同于扁球体的F拓扑中心的n次方
Internal energy of the isolated E remains constant.
孤立的E的内能仍为常量
Keep them coming, Bulkhead.
继续干 隔板
Come on.
过来
You want to finish your formula, don't you?
你想完成你的方程式 是不是？
Do you accept my proposal?
你接受我的提案吗？
Lord Megatron...
威震天陛下…
Give me a moment.
给我点时间
Did you find what you were looking for?
您找到想找的东西了吗？
It's complicated.
情况复杂
Well, Breakdown and I may have located the bogie,
嗯 击倒和我好像找到了隔板
fully charged.
充满数据的
Proceed.
说下去
Just one hitch -- we don't have the cylinder.
只有一个小问题…我们没有经筒
Then bring me the head of Bulkhead.
那就把隔板的脑袋给我带回来
Look, you love monster trucks.
看 你喜欢怪兽卡车
Remember when we snuck in here after the show last week?
记得我们上周在节目结束之后偷偷溜进这里吗？
Mass times diffusion rate squared is constant.
质量与散逸率平方乘积恒定
Is any of this ringing a bell?
所有这些就没有一样能让你想起点什么吗？
Bell curve? No, no, no,
钟形曲线？不不不
that wouldn't factor in.
那不吻合
How about our Sunday morning dune-bashings?
我们星期天早上的沙丘冲刺呢？
Rocking out to Slash Monkey?
去看歪猴子的表演呢？
Helping me with my homework?
帮我做作业呢？
Trick question!
陷阱问题！
You know I don't do homework...
你知道我不做作业…
Don't you?
对吗？
OK, forget the past.
好吧 不管过去怎样
Starting now, we can make new memories.
从现在开始我们能制造新的回忆
The cube root of the exothermic energon U delta E violates Clank's Law of energon conservation.
热能的三次根UΔE违反苦朗克能量守恒定律
Bulkhead, I know somewhere inside you always remember me,
隔板 我知道你内心的某个地方会一直记得我
and I just want you to know,
我只是想让你知道
I'll never forget you.
我永远不会忘记你
Boo hoo!
真感人！
I'm shedding lubricant.
我眼睛都要流润滑油了
Follow me right now,
现在立刻跟我走
or these guys are gonna...
否则这些家伙会…
steal the formula!
偷走方程式！
My equations?
我的方程式？
Come on, come on!
快来 快来！
Not like Bulkhead to run from a fight.
临阵脱逃并不像是隔板的作风
I'm afraid our friend has had a little too much to think.
恐怕我们的朋友是思考过度了
Lord Megatron, we are good.
威震天陛下 我们很顺利
Optimus, upon careful consideration,
擎天柱 经过我仔细的考虑
if you want the cylinder,
如果你想要经筒
you'll have to take it.
你必须自己来抢
OK, then, fun and games.
好吧 捉迷藏游戏
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
出来吧 出来吧 不管你在哪里
Ugh... the Cons are scrambling the signal.
呃…虎子们干扰了信号
The trisector the polygon is an integral subset.
多边形的三分线是不可分子集
Shhh... quiet!
嘘… 安静！
And whatever you do, keep still.
不管你做什么 别动
I'm gonna see if I can get far enough to call for backup.
我试着离远一点再请求支援
Bulkhead, is that you?
隔板 是你吗？
Breakdown, forget the human.
打击 别管那个人类了
Games are only fun to play¡­
游戏的有趣之处
¡­ when you are winning.
就是快赢的时候
I think I'm warm.
我想我赢了
EM3 devided by the square root of a propulsion factor equals...
EM3除以斥力系数的平方根等于…
You painted my paint job!
你弄脏了我的喷漆！
Prepare for surgery!
准备挨刀吧！
Heads, you lose.
你的脑袋归我了
No!
不！
Well, in that case, no one gets it.
好吧 既然如此 就谁也别想要
Optimus, Bulkhead and Miko have abandoned base.
擎天柱 隔板和神子离开了基地
I have their GroundBridge coordinates.
我有他们的环陆桥坐标
Bridge us back, immediately.
把我们传送回来 快
Not again! Get down!
又来了？趴下！
I did it again?
我又惊动它了？
Bulkhead?
隔板？
Dead battery.
废电池一只
Megatron will peel our paint for losing that data.
如果我们丢了数据 威震天会刮了我的喷漆
So we are gonna have to peel you.
所以我们必须得扒了你的皮
Or, peel out of here.
还是溜之大吉吧
Bulkhead...
隔板…
The data has been fully expelled,
数据已经被完全清除了
but Bulkhead remains completely unresponsive.
但隔板却仍然完全没有反应
Because the energy took Bulkhead's mind with it.
因为那能量将隔板的意识一起带走了
Heavenward. Lost to the stars.
飞向天际 消失在群星之间
It's my fault you'll never know the rest of the formula,
因为我的错 你们永远都不会知道方程式剩余的部分了
and it's my fault Bulkhead's gone forever.
也是因为我 隔板永远地消失了
Miko, your quick thinking prevented the formula
神子 你的机智应对
from falling into Decepticon hands.
阻止了方程式落入霸天虎手中
If anyone would've backed that plan, it's Bulkhead.
如果有谁会赞成这种行为的话 那一定是隔板
It's simply too early to know the extend of his condition.
现在就对他的状况下结论还为时过早
Something as simple as a familiar sight,
很简单的一些事 比如熟悉的景色
or smell, perhaps even a sound,
气味 甚至只是声音
could trigger Bulkhead's awakening.
都有可能唤醒隔板
Bulkhead?
隔板？
Gang... Bang...
邦… 邦…
I love that song!
我喜欢那首歌！
Miko?
神子？